

214-232-3385 <u>avschmidt63@gmail.com</u> 1143 Yorkshire Drive, Carrollton, TX 75007

Portfolio: albertoschmidt.com

## Profile

Detail-oriented, resourceful Creative Production Manager & Entrepreneurial Marketing Professional with a demonstrated work history in the advertising/design industry for clients in Retail, CPG, Healthcare, Financial, Education, and Transportation.

Extensive experience planning and implementing the delivery of content for print, digital, and out-of-home. Committed to improving processes to bring about cost savings and efficiencies and to on-time delivery without sacrificing quality.

# Experience

#### CREATIVE PRODUCTION MANAGER, THE CONTAINER STORE; DALLAS, TEXAS — 2003-PRESENT

Elevated the in-house advertising production department capabilities in the execution of in and out of store signage, magazine and newspaper ads, online banners, TV, billboards, digital asset management and 3D.

- Led and mentored in-house Production team of production designers, motion graphic, and 3D artists
- Found and implemented efficiencies in all aspects of the creative process including inhouse studio and production workflows, and asset management/delivery
- Implemented key workflow and digital asset management software, inMotion and Webdam
- Spearheaded 3D/CGI capabilities that further allowed for image versatility

#### OWNER/PRESIDENT, IMAGEN, INC.; DALLAS, TEXAS — 1993-2003

Founder of a "digital design" company servicing the production needs of major advertising, corporate and graphic design firms including Frito-Lay, GSD&M, The Richards Group, American Heart Association, Orthofix, Mary Kay, and The Container Store. Specializing in retouching, SFX, illustration and 3D.

- Pioneered the all-in-one digital production process including Art Direction, Graphic Design, Retouching, Illustration, and Animation
- Championed the adoption of digital photography

VICE PRESIDENT/SR. ART DIRECTOR, MARTINEZ/SIBONEY; DALLAS, TEXAS — 1986-1992

Directed a team of Art Directors and copywriter for full-service implementation of campaigns for Frito-Lay, Coca-Cola, Colgate-Palmolive, General Mills and Dallas Area Rapid Transit.

• Introduced one of the first fully digital advertising campaigns

### Education

The University of Texas at Austin — UX/UI Boot Camp
The University of Texas at Austin — BFA/Visual Communications

## Skills

Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, InDesign, Premiere, After Effects, Final Cut Pro, Blender, Cinema 4D, SketchUp, Invision, Figma, Webdam, Dropbox, Sharepoint, Spanish Fluent